Abracadabra Club of Washington, DC
DC Public Library, Special Collections
Abracadabra Club of Washington, DC Records
1893-1999
DC Public Library, Special Collections
8 linear feet;18 boxes
062
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series 1: Meeting Minutes, 1893-1996
  - Minutes (Bound Volume), 1893-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (Bound Volume), 1913-1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (Bound Volume), 1918-1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (Bound Volume), 1926-1933 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (Bound Volume), 1933-1938 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Related Correspondence (with no Minutes), 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Speech/Report (with no Minutes), 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1938-1955 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1955-1972 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1972-1996 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Index of Papers/Speeches/Reports, Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Index of Roll Call Responses, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Membership List, 1893-1937 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Series 2: Yearbooks, 1896-1989
  - Volume 1-3, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1920-1930 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1930-1940 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1960-1970 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1970-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1980-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Series 3: Photographs, 1966-1995, No Date
  - Dr. Abbot and Mrs. Odom, May 1966 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Abbot and Mrs. Odom, May 1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Brian - Mr. Burton and Mr. Moyer, May 1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Unknown, May 1966 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Abbot and Mr. Baker, December 1968 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Christmas Tree, December 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Floral Arrangement, December 1968 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Howard and Mr. Moyers, March 1970 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Howard and Mrs. Moyers, March 1970 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Abbot - Dr. Abbot’s 100th Birthday, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Abbot - Dr. Abbot’s 100th Birthday, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Cynthia Brooker and Betty Tibbott, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Dr. Verne Chatelain and Helen Bailey, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Negatives, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Negatives, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Negatives, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Negatives, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Negatives, April 1972 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Helen and Paul Howard - Wedding Fete, March 1975 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Gordon and Elva Webner, December 1986 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - W. Elwood Baker - 98th Birthday, November 1987 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Mr. Baker - Mrs. West - Mrs. Chatelain and Mrs. Wallman, December 1987 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Mrs. Korgen - Mrs. Tibbott and Mrs. Gettens, December 1987 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Mr. West and Mr. Wollman, December 1987 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Chatelain, March 1988 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Rebecca Hayes - Virginia Garber and Mrs. Gettens, March 1988 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Mrs. Tibbott, March 1988 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Mr. and Mrs. West and Mrs. Chatelain, May 1988 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Shirley Wilhelm and Brian Grimes, May 1988 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - W. Elwood Baker - 100th Birthday, November 1989 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - W. Elwood Baker and Mrs. Gettens, April 1990 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Chatelain, April 1990 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Katharine Gettens and Helen Howard, December 1994 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Katharine Gettens and Helen Howard, December 1994 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Tom and Jody Bramel and Betty Tibbott, October 1995 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Bob Tibbott, October 1995 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Dr. and Mrs. Abbot, Undated (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Moyer’s House, Undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Moyer’s House, Undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Moyer’s House, Undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Moyer’s House, Undated (Box 15, Folder 41)
- Series 4: Biographical Files, 1907-1999
  - Dr. Charles G. Abbot, 1907-1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Charles G. Abbot - Scrapbook, 1928-1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - R. B. Branstead, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Verne E. Chatelain, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Katharine Covella Gettens, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lois W. Howard, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Helen Day Moyer, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Obituary Scrapbook, 1906-1967 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Edward E. Odom, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Anita French Sanderson, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Gladys Harlow West, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Series 5: Financial Records, 1940-1996
  - Receipt Book, 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Receipt Book, 1945-1947 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Receipt Book, 1948-1950 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer’s Book, 1940-1961 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer’s Book, 1970-1996 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Series 6: Ephemera, 1934-1986, No Date
  - Dr. Charles G. Abbot’s Publications, 1940-1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Club Song, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Christmas Carols, 1941-1983 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Holiday Greetings, 1968-1986 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1980 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Travel Instructions, Undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Addresses/Speeches/Presentations, Undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Addresses/Speeches/Presentations, Undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Two (2) Gavels and One (1) Block, Undated (Box 18, Folder 1)